Now you learned all the theory about how components work, how you pass data around, how props work and
Teraz poznasz ca teori o tym, jak komponenty dziaaj, jak przekazujesz dane dotyczce dziaania rekwizytw i
so on
tak dalej.
and that's all nice but how do you actually plan a react application,
I to wszystko jest mie, ale jak waciwie planujesz aplikacj ponownie.
how does that work?
Jak to dziaa.
Now you can of course split this up into more granular steps than these three
Teraz moesz oczywicie podzieli to na bardziej szczegowe kroki, a nastpnie oszuka.
but here are three very important steps I see and I regularly go through when planning a react application.
Ale tutaj s trzy bardzo wane kroki, ktre widz i regularnie przechodz podczas planowania aplikacji ponownie.
The first step is planning the component tree, the component structure,
Pierwszym krokiem jest zaplanowanie struktury komponentw komponentw.
you probably get a design by your designer or you basically created an app design on your own and now
Najprawdopodobniej zostae zaprojektowany przez swojego projektanta lub sam stworzye projekt aplikacji i teraz to ty
it's up to you to split this up into react components
musisz podzieli to na komponenty, ktre ponownie dziaaj.
and it's absolutely normal that the results you may have at the end might look different than your initially
I absolutnie normalne jest to, e wyniki, jakie moesz mie na kocu, mog wyglda inaczej ni pocztkowo zaplanowany
planned component tree but it's super important to have an idea about what should go into its own component
komponent, ale bardzo wane jest, aby mie pojcie o tym, co powinno znale si we wasnym komponencie,
and what not.
a co nie.
The other important part of your application of course is the application state,
Wan czci aplikacji oczywicie jest stan aplikacji.
you can also translate this with the data you plan on using and manipulating in your application. For example
Wszyscy tumacze mog dysponowa danymi, ktre planujesz uy i ktrymi moesz manipulowa na przykad w aplikacji,
and of course you will do this over the next lectures, in our burger application,
i oczywicie zrobisz to podczas kolejnych wykadw w naszej aplikacji Bergere.
we need to keep track about the ingredients a user added because that will determine what we need to
Musimy ledzi skadniki dodane przez uytkownika, poniewa to okreli, co musimy
render and also what the user needs to pay at the end.
renderowa, a take, co uytkownik musi zapaci w kocu.
Now once you know the component structure of your application and the state you're going to use in it, you
Teraz, gdy ju znasz rozkad i struktur swojej aplikacji i stwierdzasz, e bdziesz jej uywa, nie
can plan components versus containers.
moesz planowa komponentw w porwnaniu z kontenerami.
So which components in your application should be stateless or functional,
Wic ktre skadniki w aplikacji powinny by bezpastwowcami lub funkcjonalne.
sometimes also referred to as dumb components and which components have to be stateful components
Czasami okrelane rwnie jako gupie komponenty i komponenty, ktre musz by penymi komponentami stanu utworzonymi za
created with that class keyword because they need to manage some state and distribute it down to their
pomoc sowa kluczowego tej klasy, poniewa musz one zarzdza pewnym stanem i dystrybuowa je
dumber components, to the stateless components.
do swoich gupich skadnikw do stanu mniej skadnikw.
These are the three steps I regularly go through and these are the steps I want to go through with you together.
S to trzy kroki, ktre regularnie przechodz i s to kroki, ktre chc przej z gabrem.
We're going to plan our component tree, component structure and then we're going to have a look at which
Zamierzamy zaplanowa struktur komponentw komponentw, a nastpnie sprawdzimy, ktry stan jest nam potrzebny
state we need and what can be a component and what should be a container
i jaki moe by komponent oraz jaki powinien by kontener.
and then we're just going to start building the application.
A potem zaczniemy budowa aplikacj.
And as you will see we might then even add more components than we initially planned because we see that
Jak wida, moemy nawet doda wicej komponentw, ni pocztkowo planowalimy, poniewa widzimy, e
we can split up even more
moemy dzieli jeszcze wicej.
or maybe that some split
A moe to jaki rozam.
we did plan doesn't make sense once we start implementing it and that's perfectly normal.
Zrobilimy plan, ktry nie ma sensu, kiedy zaczniemy go wdraa i to jest zupenie normalne.
But having a plan is of course very important.
Ale posiadanie planu jest oczywicie bardzo wane.